Hello, and welcome back. In this video, I want to discuss a very
大家好 欢迎回来 在这节视频中 我们将讨论
important technique for image, and also video segmentation and other image
一种应用于图像和视频分割 以及其他图像处理方法中的重要技术
processing techniques. And that's what is called graph cats, as
如我们所见 那就是图像分割技术
we see here. And I'm going to illustrate that with a
接下来 我将用一幅简单的图像为大家阐述图像分割技术
very simple figure and then we're going to provide some examples.
然后给出几个例子
So, what is graph cats? Let's start from a simple image.
首先 什么是图像分割？让我们从一幅简单的图像说起
White and black. And the basic idea of graph cut is to
这是一幅黑白图像 图像分割的基本思想就是
borrow tools from graph theory to partition this image into foreground and
借助图论的一些工具 将一幅图划分为前景和背景
background. So we are going to tilt the image, just
为了更直观 我们将这幅图像倾斜
for the sake of illustration, and we're going to take one line across the image,
然后在图像中间取一条线
as we see here. So we take one line.
就像这样 我们取这一条线
And basically, we're going to represent that line here.
然后 要把这条线表示出来
Every pixel is going to be a node on a graph that we are going to build in just
在我们将要构建的图像上 每一个像素都会表示为一个节点
a second. So these represent pixels in a very cold
这些节点粗略地表示每个像素
fashion. Just to illustrate, every pixel, one node
为了方便描述 图像中的每一个节点就代表一个像素
in the image. And now we're going to add two nodes.
现在 我们要添加两种节点
One, which we call the sink and that's going to be represent by background
一种被称为“汇节点” 用来代表背景像素
pixels. And the other is going to be the source,
另一种被称为“源节点”
and that's going to be representing the foreground pixels.
用来代表前景像素
Once again, we have, for every pixel in the image a note, so there would be a lot
重复一遍 图像中每个像素表示为一个节点 所以这里会出现很多节点
of notes here. You can think about a graph that is
大家可以想象一幅平面的图像
planar, in, for those images,
像这个一样
and then you can think about basically putting a source and a sink.
然后在这里放了一个源节点和汇节点
So we have a lot of here, we have a lot of basically planar nodes and we have a
我们有很多在平面上的节点
node on the top and a node on the bottom. So now we have the nodes on the graphs,
以及在顶部和底部的两个节点 现在我们已经有了图像中的节点
on the graph, we need now to construct the edges.
接下来要做的就是构造边
How do we connect these nodes? First of all, how do we connect every
怎样把这些节点连起来呢 首先 我们要考虑
node representing a pixel to the foreground, source, and to the background
怎样把代表每个像素的节点 和代表前景的源节点 以及代表背景的汇节点连起来
sink? And the basic idea is that we connect
基本思想就是
them with some measurement of the probability of the node, meaning the
根据每一个像素点可能成为前景或者背景的概率
pixel being background, or being foreground.
进行度量 然后将它们连起来
So for every pixel in the image, we've got a node,
也就是说 图像中的每个像素点 都用一个节点来表示
and we look at that node, and somehow we say, what's your
然后观察这些节点 它成为前景的概率有多大
probability of being foreground? And we connect that to the source with
然后按照由概率所决定的权重 将其与源节点连起来
the weight related to that probability. That's the weight of the edge.
这也就是边的权重
And then we ask, what's your probability of being background?
同样的 我们考虑这个节点成为背景的概率有多大
And we use that probability to connect, to define the weight of the age that
然后用这个概率来决定 该节点与代表背景的汇节点相连的边的权重
connects to the background sink. How can we compute those probabilities?
那么 怎样来计算概率呢？
For example as we saw in the previous video if we are in an interactive system
举个例子 就像我们在前面的视频中看到的 如果这是一个交互式的系统
we can get different scribbles, exactly as we saw in the previous video.
我们会得到不同的涂抹 参见上一个视频
You can use information of this surrounding pixels. So that's very open,
我们可以利用这些周围像素的信息 所以这是很开放的
and it's part of the sign of the algorithm but the simplest is as we saw
而且是算法设计中的一部分 但是就像前一个视频中所说
in the previous video to use information from the scribbles.
最简单的方法是利用那些涂抹的信息
So now we have connected every node, meaning every pixel to the source,
现在我们连好了每一个节点 意味着每个像素和前景节点以及背景节点都连起来了
and to the background sink. Next, we need to connect the pixels among
接下来 我们需要在像素点之间互相连接
themselves. So we are going to also construct edges
也就是说 通过像素点之间的互相连接
connecting pixels among themselves. In particular we are only going to
来构造边 特别地 我们只需连接相邻的两个像素点
connect to the neighboring pixels, meaning the neighboring nodes.
换句话说 就是连接相邻节点
So the one on your right, the one above you,
也就是连接右面的点 或上面的点
below you, on your left, maybe diagonals. We talked very early on in this class
下面的点 左面的点 或者是对角线上的点
about for neighborhood and a neighborhood.
在课程初期我们就谈论过4邻域和8邻域的概念
We will probably use only one of those. And now the question is, what's the
在这里 只用其中一种 现在的问题是
weight on these edges? And I want you to think for a second,
如何衡量边的权重 我希望你思考一下
what would you put here. Has to be something that helps you in the
你会怎么做  这个操作需要有助于你进行图像分割
segmentation. So why don't you think for a second, and
为什么不先自己思考一会儿呢？
write it in the inline quiz that I'm presenting and tell me what do you think
然后在视频中的小测中写下来 告诉我
should be there, the weights. Thank you very much for thinking about
关于权重你是怎么想的 非常感谢大家思考这个问题
the question I just asked. The weight basically has to be something
实际上 权重就是使得相似的像素点
that promote pixels that are very similar to stay together to stay in the same
尽量保持在同一个部分中
segment, and pixels that are very different promotes them to become
而不同的像素点尽量被分割到不同的部分中
different segments, foreground and background.
从而区分前景和背景
For example, we could put weights that are proportional to the gradient.
举个例子 我们可以让权重与梯度成比例
We can put weights that are proportional to the difference of pixel values or the
我们可以设置权重 使其正比于像素值之差
difference of the pixel values in the neighborhood of the pixel.
或者具体的说 正比于该像素值与相邻像素值之差
So anything that will promote similar pixels, and we have to define similarity
因此 我们必须根据不同应用 来定义相似点
depending on the application, anything that promotes similar pixels to stay
以确定哪些是相似的像素 使它们划分到一块
together, and different pixels to become a part
并区分不同像素
foreground and background. Once we have constructed a whole graph,
形成前景和背景 一旦构造出了整个图
then we call graph theory, and we're going to partition that graph.
然后我们应用图论 就可以分割图像了
So we're going to create what's called a mint cut.
接下来我们就可以构建最小割 (min cut)
That's a cut with minimal effort, minimal price, and it's going to try, to cut,
这是一种花费最小的分割方法 它试图
foreground from, notes, that are very weak, so this had a high probability of
从最弱的节点开始分割前景 意味着其成为背景的概率很大
being back ground, low, of being fore ground, so the graph can is going to try
而成为前景的概率很低 于是图像将从该点进行切割
to cut it out, cut it out, it's going to try to go.
再切割 并继续往下进行
Once we are on the plane of the plane that corresponds to the pixels values is
当进行到 对应于像素值的节点平面上时
going to try to go through edges that basically, we told the algorithm that
我们将尝试穿过像素之间的边
those edges are connecting pixels that are very different.
并且告知算法 这些边所连接的像素有很大差异
And they are probably should be in different regions.
因此这些像素很可能需要分在不同的区域
So it's going to try to cut the weak edges, because it's going to add the
所以 最小割试图切断弱连接的边 因为它会增加切割的代价
price the cut pace, is the addition of the weights of the edges it's.
这个代价正是 被切割的边的权重之和
cutting through. So it's going to try to cut through weak edges,
就这样 试图切断弱连接的边
and in that, and in that way, it's going to separate the foreground from the
以这种方式分离前景和背景
background. Now, there are good techniques to do
现在 我们有了很好的技术来实现这个过程
that, and that can achieve this in polynomial time, so there are very
而且可以在多项式时间获得求解
efficient ways to solve this mean cut problem, and.
也就是说 我们可以非常高效地解决这个最小割问题
By that, we got the seperation between the foreground and the background, this
然后通过这种方法 成功分离前景和背景
technique, can be actually extended, to multiple objects in the image, not just
这种技术也可以扩展到 分割图像中的多种物体
foreground and background, and, other type of input data.
不仅仅是前景和背景 还包括其他形式的输入数据
But it's easier to illustrate when we think about just, one source and one
但是当我们考虑一个源节点和一个汇节点时 阐述起来会更简单
sink, meaning foreground. And background separate.
也就是前景和背景的分离
So, two steps, basically. One is construct the graph.
所以 只需两步 第一步 构造图
Second step, produce the main cut. The second step,
第二步 产生最小割
basically, a very good algorithms in graph theory.
第二步中 会用到图论中一个很好的算法
The first step of constructing the graph is what the image processing information
第一步构造图是指 将图像处理的信息转化到图中
comes into the graph. Let us illustrate a few examples.
下面给大家讲几个例子
So, here we see examples where basically in the examples I'm showing they borrow,
这里我们可以看到一些例子
as I say at the very beginning, from the graph cut technique, that provides kind
像之前说的那样 通过基于背景涂抹的图割技术
of a scribble in the background, and here we see the segmentation.
得到这里所看到图像分割
A second example here and a third example here.
第二个和第三个例子也是这样
And once again, these can be run very, very fast.
再次提醒 这个运算过程会非常非常快速
And here I'm going to illustrate a very nice example an application of this.
下面我为大家展示一个非常棒的应用该技术的例子
So we go into one picture of this trip and segment it out.
现在我们在一次旅行中选取一张照片 将其分割
And put it in the large picture and then you do the same for the next one.
然后放入一张大图片里 下面的图像也这么做
Segment it out using the technique I just explained and go and put it in the
用刚刚所讲的技术将其分割 继续放进这张大图中
picture. And then you repeat it for the other
然后对其他照片重复应用这个步骤
ones. And you end up having, a new, image that
最后通过剪切和粘贴
is basically a composite of multiple images through this, cut and paste.
得到一幅组合了许多图像的新的图像
I think it's a very nice example, and a very nice application of this.
我觉得这是很棒的例子
Interactive type of image segmentation in this particular case through prod cards
是交互式图像分割技术的一个很好的应用
which is a particular implementation a very smart technique really to this
在这里例子中 运用了有关最小割或图割技术的巧妙实现
minimum card or this graph cards technique.
来进行图像分割
What I want to conclude is by explaining to you that this type of technique
我想总结的是 这种类型的技术
actually is incorporated in Microsoft Office.
已经被并入了微软的Office软件中
So this is very modern image processing that as we have seen in other examples
所以 正如我们在一些例子中已经见到的
and we are going to see in future examples actually right after,
以及在之后的视频中将要见到的
this video, these techniques get into some of the very popular pieces of
这是一种非常现代化的图像处理技术 而且已经被一些人们常用的流行软件所采纳
software that many people use. Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家
See you in the next video.
我们下一个视频再见